Profile

An experienced and talented technical writer, I create task-based documentation tailored for target audiences - the right documentation, at the right time, via the right channel.

I am passionate about user experience, content strategy, and open standards such as DITA. I am interested in exploring the ways Agile methodologies and cloud-based infrastructure can improve content development and hosting.

CORE EXPERTISE

Research & Analysis • Strategic Planning • Project & Program Management • Information Architecture • Quality Assurance

Experience

INFOR-ST PAUL, MN

TECHNICAL PROGRAM MANAGER - 06/2021-10/2022

Served as lead information architect and project manager of strategic initiatives for the global information development (infodev) department

Coordinated, tracked, and reported on strategic projects

Coach for Information Architects, who administer, develop, and maintain infodev authoring tools, CCMS, and content presentation frameworks among other products

Developed and managed process for infodev tooling and other internal project work intake and defined and maintained a work prioritization process to help create focus and ensure projects were resourced and work completed

Drove adoption and reinforcement of Agile development methodologies

Collaborated with other departments on projects such as: implementing a search solution for the docs website, ongoing development and rollout of the embedded user-assistance app/widget, defining documentation versioning practices and standards

Managed the architecture, delivery, and maintenance of the public-facing docs.infor.com documentation site, fulfilling several roles as needed, such as QA, developer, release manager

Acted as department liaison and SME for AWS architecture, accounts, and services and Infor DevOps tools and processes

PRINCIPAL INFORMATION DEVELOPER - 09/2013-06/2021

Half time content creator, half time information architect

Designed and developed a hosted model for docs, including web apps and API on AWS

Designed and managed project to create API-based embedded user assistance app

Implemented and supported DITA-based CCMS

Devised and instituted content strategy for product doc, as well as information architecture and design of online help

Charity Fretty charityfretty@gmail.com

Designed and wrote administrator and end user product documentation for Java-based technology platform

HEALTHLAND- MINNEAPOLIS, MN

TECHNICAL WRITER - 10/2011-09/2013

Authored and updated documentation for healthcare software solutions and third-party products, including installation and configuration instructions, reference guides, and online help for internal and external audiences

Created release materials and client communications for frequent product releases, which generally entailed one large release and quarterly and monthly patches

Collaborated in the administration, QA testing, maintenance, and design of the client portal and LMS, including the development and design of a knowledge base

Organized and led a client focus group to solicit feedback on end user deliverables and to gain insight on client portal adoption

LAWSON SOFTWARE- ST PAUL, MN

LEAD INFORMATION DEVELOPER – 12/2008-10/2011

Planned, wrote, and edited documentation for landmark and legacy applications for the healthcare and public sector industries, including user and administration guides and interface/integration documentation

Assisted in the design and roll out of new documentation presentations, including Eclipse Infocenters for online content libraries and help systems

Identified and lead strategic information development infrastructure initiatives and worked with senior management to determine priorities, costs, and resourcing of projects

Supported and mentored the global writing and translation team on tooling and processes

Collaborated in the design, testing, roll out, and training of customizations to CMS and XML authoring tools to improve quality and productivity

Implemented issue tracking software for the operations team

Created of a strategic project vision for presentation to development leadership

Managed the upgrade of company's CMS software with minimal disruption to the writing team

Early Career

MANAGER, INFORMATION DEVELOPMENT, LAWSON SOFTWARE 06/2005-12/2008

INFORMATION DEVELOPER, LAWSON SOFTWARE 03/2001-06/2005

CONSULTANT, INFORMATION DESIGN SERVICES, SPHERION 12/1998-03/2001

TECHNICAL WRITER, CIPRICO 01/1997-12/1998

Education

Minnesota State University, Moorhead – B.A. English and Mass Communications, 1996

Charity Fretty charityfretty@gmail.com

Skills

CCMS (IXIASOFT CCMS) * XML authoring tools (Oxygen, XMetaL, Arbortext) * HTML * Read, understand, and write simple code: json, JavaScript, yaml, regex, java, sql * Wiki (Confluence) * Issue tracking and project management (Jira, Roadmunk) * Cloud-hosted applications and services (AWS, containerization, microservice architecture) * Adobe Technical Communications Suite (Acrobat Pro, FrameMaker, RoboHelp) * MS Office Suite and flowcharts and diagramming tools (Lucidchart, Visio) * Source code management (git, GitLab)